A Guide to the Richmond (Va.) Office of the City Engineer, Records, 1809-1975
Library of Virginia
- Series I. Architectural drawings and plans, 1809-1975.
  - Cemetery - Map / of / Riverview Cemetery / Showing Divisions, Plats & Roads, 40-B-5, n.d., Dimensions: 30-1/4 x 45 in. - 77 x 114 cm.; Scale: 1" = 60'; Media: India ink on linen with pencil notations; Sheets: 1 (Folder 18)
  - Cemetery - Riverview [Plan of lots in four circular sections], 2-A-6, n.d., Dimensions: 19 x 19 in. - 48 x 48 cm.; Scale: None; Media: Pencil, India ink, and red ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 18)
  - Cemetery - Divisions 8 11, & 12, 45-A-6c, n.d., Dimensions: 21-3/4 x 26 in. - 55 x 66 cm.; Scale: 1"= 20'; Media: Pencil and India ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 15)
  - Cemetery - Parts A, B, C, D, & H of Circles, 45-A-6g, n.d., Dimensions: 22-1/2 x 26-1/2 in. - 57 x 66 cm.; Scale: 1" = 20'; Media: India ink and brown ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 15)
  - Cemetery - Shockoe Hill Cemetery [plan of lots], 19-C-1, n.d., Dimensions: 51 x 34-1/2 in. - 130 x 88 cm.; Scale: None; Media: India ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 93)
  - Cemetery - Plat C / Div. #1 / Showing Sections & Paths., 43-A-6, n.d., Dimensions: 17 x 27-3/4 in. - 43 x 71 cm.; Scale: 1" = 10'; Media: Pencil and India ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 18)
  - Cemetery - Divisions 3, 4, 6, & 7, 45-A-6e, n.d., Dimensions: 21-1/2 x 28-1/2 in. - 54 x 71 cm.; Scale: 1" = 20'; Media: India ink and brown ink with pencil notations on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 15)
  - Cemetery - [Partial plan of Hollywood Cemetery and the Clarke Springs property], 28-A-2, n.d., Dimensions: 16-1/2 x 45 in. - 42 x 114 cm.; Scale: 1" = 50'; Media: India ink and brown ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 14)
  - Cemetery - River View Cemetery - Division .. / Plan of Lots, etc., 10575-B-1, n.d., Dimensions: 25-1/4 x 31 in. - 64 x 79 cm.; Scale: None; Media: Pencil, India ink, and red ink on heavy paper with cloth backing; Sheets: 1 (Folder 18)
    Drawn By: Office of City Engineer / Richmond, Virginia
  - Cemetery - [Working drawing of layout of Oakwood cemetery], 8-B-5, n.d., Dimensions: 29-1/2 x 41-1/4 in. - 75 x 105 cm.; Scale: None; Media: Pencil, India ink, and red ink on heavy paper with cloth backing. Extensive pencil notations; Sheets: 1 (Folder 16)
  - Cemetery - [Plan of two sections of Oakwood Cemetery], 10119-B-1, n.d., Dimensions: 24 x 34-1/4 in. - 61 x 87 cm.; Scale: None; Media: Pencil, India ink, and red ink on heavy paper (brittle and damaged); Sheets: 1 (Folder 16)
  - Cemetery - Plan of Coping around Col. W. E. Cutshaw's Section in Hollywood Cemetery, 17-D-4, n.d., Dimensions: 19-1/2 x 36 in. - 49 x 91 cm.; Scale: 1" = 1'; Media: India ink and red ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 14)
  - Cemetery - Division XXXVII. [Maury cemetery], [No file number], n.d., Dimensions: 18 x 23-1/2 in. - 46 x 60 cm.; Scale: 1" = 30'; Media: Photostatic print on paper; Sheets: 1 (Folder 15)
  - Cemetery - Divisions 26 to 34 inclusive, [No file number], n.d., Dimensions: 16 x 29 in. - 41 x 74 cm.; Scale: 1" = 20'; Media: India ink, brown ink, and pencil notations on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 15)
  - Cemetery - Divisions 18 to 25 Inclusive [Maury Cemetery (?)], 45-A-6f, n.d., Dimensions: 22-1/2 x 27-1/2 in. - 57 x 70 cm.; Scale: 1" = 20'; Media: India ink and brown ink on linen with pencil notations; Sheets: 1 (Folder 15)
  - City Hall - [Richmond City Hall - plan], 2-H-3, 1816, Dimensions: Service Copy: 31.75 x 25 cm; Original: 25 x 37 cm.; Scale: 1" = 16'; Media: Service copy: Dye-sub print; Original: Pricking and ink on paper; Sheets: 1 (Folder 20)
    Drawn By: [Robert Mills]
  - City Hall - [Richmond City Hall], [No file number], 1884, Dimensions: 39-1/2 x 54 in. - 100 x 137 cm.; Scale: 1" = 4'; Media: Pencil (?), India ink, red ink, and blue ink on linen with various ink and pencil notations; positive photostat; Sheets: 6 (Folder Super-OS 4, Dwr. 3)
    Drawn By: E. E. Myers Arch't. / Detroit - Mich.; CD # 111.
  - City Hall - Case for Sewer Maps, 27-A-2, 1897, Dimensions: 14-1/2 x 32-1/2 in. - 37 x 83 cm.; Scale: 1/8" = 1"; Media: India ink and red ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 20)
  - City Hall - Proposed Steel Equipment for / City Engineer's Office / Richmond, Va, [No file number], 1915, Dimensions: 16-3/4 x 29-1/2 in. - 42 x 75 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: Blueprint; Sheets: 2 (Folder 20)
    Drawn By: Submitted by / Crown Metal Construction Co. / Jamestown, N.Y.
  - City Hall - [Plans for map cabinets], [No file number], 1917, Dimensions: 12 x 17 in. - 31 x 43 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: Blueprint; Sheets: 1 (Folder 20)
    Drawn By: Submitted by Everett Waddy Co. Richmond, Va.
  - City Hall - City Engineer's Office / Plan Showing Location of Furniture, 60-C-2, 1917, Dimensions: 25 x 39-1/2 in. - 64 x 100 cm.; Scale: 1/4" = 1'; Media: India ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 20)
  - City Hall - Plan of Offices / Department of Public Works / Showing Location of Furniture, 11168-A-6, 1921, Dimensions: 25-1/2 x 40 in. - 65 x 102 cm.; Scale: 1/4" = 1'; Media: India ink on tracing paper (damaged); Sheets: 1 (Folder 20)
    Drawn By: Department of Public Works / Bureau of Surveys, Sewers & Bridges / Richmond, Virginia
  - City Hall - Proposed Metal Cases for / City Engineer's Office / Richmond, Va., 11016-A-6, n.d., Dimensions: 13-3/4 x 31-3/4 in. - 35 x 81 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: Blueprint; Sheets: 2 (Folder 20)
  - City Hall - Blue-Print Frame, Carriage and Track / for / City Engineer's Office / City Hall, Richmond, Va., 16-B-4, n.d., Dimensions: Various; Scale: Various; Media: 1 India ink and red ink on linen, 1 pencil and India ink on heavy paper; Sheets: 2 (Folder 20)
  - City Hall - Storm Door / City Hall, 18-A-1, n.d., Dimensions: 25-3/4 x 16-1/4 in. - 66 x 41 cm.; Scale: 1" = 1'; Media: India ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 20)
  - Electrical - [Plan of poles along Broad Street between Madison and 10th streets], [No file number], 1900, Dimensions: 8 x 47-1/2 in. - 20 x 121 cm.; Scale: 1" = 100'; Media: India ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 21)
  - Electrical - [Large city map showing position of electrical poles and routes of lines], 38-43-D-3, 1910, Dimensions: Various; Scale: None; Media: Blueprint with red ink notations; Sheets: 9 (Folder 21)
    Drawn By: Signature of approval by Charles Bolling, City Engineer, Nov. 18, 1910
  - Electrical - Manhole Frame & Cover, 36-D-3, 1910, Dimensions: 18 x 28 in. - 46 x 71 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: India ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 21)
    Drawn By: McCay Engineering Co. / Baltimore, MD
  - Electrical - Proposed Underground Conduit System / For the City of Richmond, Va., 37-D-3, 1910, Dimensions: 9 x 65 in. - 23 x cm.; Scale: None; Media: Blueprint; Sheets: 1 (Folder 21)
    Drawn By: Mc Cay Engineering Co. Balto. MD.
  - Electrical - Extension Broad Street Lighting, 13-D-3a, 1911, Dimensions: 15-1/2 x 34 in. - 39 x 87 cm.; Scale: None; Media: Blueprint with ink notations; Sheets: 1 (Folder 21)
    Drawn By: E.W. Trafford Consulting Engineer
  - Electrical - Plan of Pole Setting / Broad Street, 37-D-3, 1911, Dimensions: 16-1/2 x 19 in. - 42 x 48 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: Blueprint; Sheets: 1 (Folder 21)
    Drawn By: Appd / Chas. E. Bolling / City Engr.
  - Electrical - City Electric Plant / Richmond, Va. / Plan, Profile and Cross Sections / Masonry Arch Culvert Under James River / and Kanawha Canal and Chesapeake & Ohio Ry., 10651-B-1, 1918, Dimensions: 24-1/2 x 32 in. - 62 x 81 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: Pencil and India ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 21)
  - Electrical - [Map of town of Highland Park showing electrical poles, streetlights and status of wiring of residences], 10149-B-1, n.d., Dimensions: 36 x 21-1/4 in. - 92 x 54 cm.; Scale: 1" = 300'; Media: Blueprint (damaged); Sheets: 1 (Folder 21)
  - Electrical - [Plan of utility poles and routes], 55-C-1, n.d., Dimensions: 25-1/4 x 35 in. - 64 x 89 cm.; Scale: None; Media: Blueline print with ink and red ink notations; Sheets: 1 (Folder 21)
  - Electrical - Proposed Under Ground Conduit System, 35-D-3, n.d., Dimensions: 27 x 32 in. - 68 x 81 cm.; Scale: None; Media: Blueprint with ink notations; Sheets: 1 (Folder 21)
    Drawn By: Mc Cay Engineering Co. / Baltimore, MD.
  - Electrical - City of Richmond Electric Plant. / Underground System, 35-D-3, n.d., Dimensions: 19 x 37 in. - 48 x 94 cm.; Scale: None; Media: 1 India ink on linen, 2 blueprints; Sheets: 3 (Folder 21)
    Drawn By: E.W. Trafford / Consulting Engineer / Richmond, Va. / Installed by / McCay Engineering Co. / Baltimore, MD
  - Fire Department - [Steamer Company No. 5], 15-B-2, [1883], Dimensions: Various; Scale: None; Media: 4 Pricking, pencil, India ink, and red ink on paper, 1; Sheets: 5 (Folder 81)
  - Gas Works - Plan & Profile of Proposed New Street / to be Opened on Gas House Property / from Intersection of Maple St. and Southern / to Poplar St., 32-C-3, 1909, Dimensions: 23 x 35-3/4 in. - 58 x 91 cm.; Scale: 1" =20'; Media: India ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 22)
    Drawn By: Office of City Engr. / Richmond, Va.
  - Gas Works - Buildings / Lower Gas Works / Between Williamsburg Ave. & / Gillies Creek, E. & W. of Maple Street, 10528-B-1, 1918, Dimensions: 24-1/2 x 36 in. - 62 x 92 cm.; Scale: 1" = 20'; Media: India ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 22)
  - Gas Works - Proposed Railroad Connection / The City Gas Works / Richmond, Va., 10927-C-3, 1920, Dimensions: 26-1/2 x 74 in. - 67 x 188 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: Blueprint; Sheets: 1 (Folder 22)
    Drawn By: Forstall & Robison / Consulting Engineers / New York
  - Jail - Revised Plan of Widths of Walls of / Boiler and Coal Vaults at City Jail, 10-D-4, 1901, Dimensions: 14-1/4 x 25-1/2 in. - 36 x 65 cm.; Scale: 1/4" = 1'; Media: Blueprint; Sheets: 1 (Folder 24)
    Drawn By: S. Ed. Bates / Asst. City Engr.
  - Jail - Table showing sizes of air flues, ducts, smoke & vent shafts for City Jail, 15-D-1, 1901, Dimensions: 29-1/4 x 21-1/4 in. - 74 x 54 cm.; Scale: None; Media: Blueprint; Sheets: 1 (Folder 24)
    Drawn By: [approval signatures of City Engineer and Chairman of Committee on Buildings and Grounds]
  - Jail - Jail Building for City of Richmond, Virginia, 10-DR-19, 1901-1902, Dimensions: 21 x 50 (and smaller); Scale: 1/4 in. = 1ft.; Media: Pencil, India ink, red and blue ink on linen; Sheets: 44 (Folder Roll 15)
    Drawn By: The Stewart Iron Works, Prison Architects and Builders, Cincinnati, O[H] Approved W. E. Cutshaw, City Engineer Approved Committee on Grounds and Buildings, William G. Gibson, Chairman
  - Jail - Electrical Layout for the City Jail, Richmond, Virginia, Y-12324, 1922, Dimensions:; Scale: 1/4" = 1'; Media: Blueprints; Sheets: 6 (Folder Roll 14)
    Drawn By: Carneal & Johnston, Architects & Engineers, Richmond, Virginia
  - Jail - Juvenile / Detention Home / for the / City of Richmond / Richmond, Virginia, Y-13541, 1956, Dimensions: 30 x 42 in. - 76 x 107 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: Blueprints; Sheets: 18 (Folder Roll 15)
    Drawn By: Carneal & Johnston / Architects & Engineers / Atlantic Life Bldg. -- Richmond, Va.
  - Jail - Plan / Showing Arrangement / of / Present City Jail, 31-A-2, n.d., Dimensions: 16-1/4 x 35 in. - 41 x 89 cm.; Scale: 1/8" = 1'; Media: India ink on linen; Sheets: 5 (Folder 24)
  - Jail - [Jail building plan], 16-A-2, n.d., Dimensions: 16-1/4 x 42-1/2 in. - 41 x 108 cm.; Scale: 1" = 4'; Media: Pencil, India ink, and red ink on heavy paper (damaged); Sheets: 2 (Folder 25)
  - Jail - Plan No. 202 [Plans for unidentified jail building], 16-B-2, n.d., Dimensions: 19-1/2 x 35-3/4 in. - 49 x 91 cm.; Scale: 1/4" = 1'; Media: Blueprint; Sheets: 11 (Folder 24)
  - Jail - Present Jail Space / between guard walls / on all four sides, 8-C-3, n.d., Dimensions: 23-3/4 x 36-1/4 in. - 60 x 92 cm.; Scale: 1" = 10'; Media: India ink and red ink on linen (damaged); Sheets: 1 (Folder 24)
  - Jail - Jail Building / for / City of Richmond, Va., 17-A-2, n.d., Dimensions: 21 x 49-1/2 in. - 53 x 126 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: Blueprints with various pencil and ink notations; Sheets: 21 (Folder 23)
    Drawn By: The Stewart Iron Wks. - Prison Architects and Builders / Cincinnati, O
  - Map - A / Plan / of / the City of / Richmond, [No file number], 1809, Dimensions: 23-3/4 x 40-1/2 in. - 60 x 103 cm.; Scale: 1" = 400'; Media: Printed and colored map with various ink notations on heavy cloth backing; Sheets: 1 (Folder 95)
    Drawn By: To / the Citizens of Richmond this Plan / is respectfully inscribed by their / Obedient Servant / Richard Young
  - Map - [verso] Survey Price & OthersOthers made the of November 1811, 36-A-5, 1811, Dimensions: 12 x 12-3/4 in. - 31 x 32 cm.; Scale: 1" = 20'; Media: Pricking and iron gall ink on paper (damaged) mounted on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 97)
    Drawn By: [John Wood (?)]
  - Map - Plan of the City of / Richmond / Drawn form Actual Surveys and Original Plans, [No file number], 1835, Dimensions: 25-1/2 x 39-3/4 in. - 65 x 101 cm.; Scale: 1" = 400'; Media: Printed colored map on heavy cloth backing; Sheets: 1 (Folder 96)
    Drawn By: By Michiah Bates
  - Map - Surveyed for Arch Hughes the Lots of Ground on this plat, 11-A-6, 1836, Dimensions: 14 x 17 in. - 35 x 43 cm.; Scale: None; Media: Ink and green ink on heavy paper mounted on modern drafting linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 97)
    Drawn By: Micajah Bates City Surveyor
  - Map - Surveyed for Adam Miller the 4 lots on this plan / Marked O in Col. A Plan, 35-A-5, 1838, Dimensions: 12 x 10-1/2 in. - 31 x 27 cm.; Scale: None; Media: Pricking, scoring, and pen and ink on paper mounted on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 97)
    Drawn By: Micajah Bates, City Surveyor
  - Map - Map of / Condemnation / by / Richard Young / Richmond, 9th. of November 1827 / The above is a true copy made by me / on file in the James River Company offices / taken to be used in a suit Neilson vs. / Haxall April 1851, 16-A-5, 1851 (?), Dimensions: 29-1/2 x 56-1/2 in. - 75 x 143 cm.; Scale: None; Media: Pencil, ink, and yellow ink on paper with pencil notations; Sheets: 1 (Folder 98)
    Drawn By: Thos. M. Ladd S.C.R.
  - Map - James River [Hydrographic survey of river downstream of Mayo's Bridge], 30-B-5, 1854, Dimensions: 36-1/4 x 19-1/4 in. - 92 x 49 cm.; Scale: 1" = 5000"; Media: Pen and ink on paper; Sheets: 1 (Folder 28)
    Drawn By: Traced by Thos. Wm. Eg
  - Map - Plan of Navy Hill, 33-13-5, 1854, Dimensions: 31 x 36 in.; Scale: None; Media: Pencil, ink, and colored inks on heavy paper; Sheets: 1 (Folder 82)
    Drawn By: Thos. M. Ladd, C. R. S.
  - Map - Campaign Maps - Army of the Potomac / Map No. 2 / Williamsburg to White House, 7-A-3, 1862, Dimensions: 27-1/4 x 24-1/2 in. - 69 x 62 cm.; Scale: 1" = 1 mile; Media: Blueprint of photographic reduction of original; Sheets: 1 (Folder 27)
    Drawn By: This map compiled by / Capt. HL. Abbot, Top. Eng'rs
  - Map - Richmond [map of defenses around Richmond showing opposing lines], [No file number], 1867, Dimensions: 24 x 34-1/4 in. - 61 x 87 cm.; Scale: 1-1/2" = 1 mile; Media: Printed map with blue and red notations; Sheets: 11 (Folder 105)
    Drawn By: By Command of / Bvt. Maj. Genl. A. A. Humphreys, Brig. Genl. & Chief of Engineers
  - Map - North Anna [map of opposing lines of battle], [No file number], 1867, Dimensions: 17 x 24 in. - 43 x 61 cm.; Scale: 3" = 1 mile; Media: Printed map with blue and red notations (very poor condition; in two pieces); Sheets: 1 (Folder 105)
  - Map - Spottsylvania Court House, 25-A-4, 1867, Dimensions: 21-3/4 x 32 in. - 56 x 81 cm.; Scale: 3" = 1 mile; Media: Printed map with blue and red notations on cloth backing; Sheets: 1 (Folder 105)
  - Map - Map / of / Gillies & Shockoe Creek / Watersheds, Y-7720, 1874, Dimensions: 36-1/2 x 55-1/2 in. - 92 x 141 cm.; Scale: 1" = 1000'; Media: Pencil, ink, and light wash on heavy paper with cloth backing; Sheets: 1 (Folder Roll 7)
    Drawn By: W. E. Cutshaw City Engineer
  - Map - Sketch / of the Battlefield / and / Confederate Works In Front Of / Williamsburg, Va. / May 5th. 1862, 23-A-4, 1876, Dimensions: 13 x 14 in. - 33 x 36 cm.; Scale: 1" = 600'; Media: Printed map with red and blue notations; Sheets: 1 (Folder 105)
    Drawn By: [Office of the Chief of Engineers U. S. Army]
  - Map - The / Town of Sidney, 32-B-5, 1887, Dimensions: 23-1/4 x 38 in. - 59 x 97 cm.; Scale: 1" = 20 rods; Media: Pencil, India ink, and various colored inks on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 26)
    Drawn By: Made for use of the City Engrs. Office by E.T.D. Meyers Jr.
  - Map - Map of / the / Wm. C. Allen / Addition / Richmond / Va., 11137-C-2, 1888, Dimensions: 39-1/4 x 23 in. - 100 x 58 cm.; Scale: 1" = 70'; Media: Printed map on paper with taped backing; Sheets: 1 (Folder 28)
    Drawn By: Bates & Bolton Engineers -- GWm Baist / 806 Walnut Phila.
  - Map - Map of the Lands of the West-End Land and / Improvement Company, situated a short distance west / of the City of Richmond in Henrico County / Drawn from Original Surveys, 43-B-5, 1889, Dimensions: 32-3/4 x 38-1/4 in. - 83 x 97 cm.; Scale: None; Media: India ink, red ink, and pencil notations on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 26)
    Drawn By: James T. Reed & Sons
  - Map - Map of / Lee District. / A Copy of the City's Map of Feb. 29 1892, 8-D-1, 1895, Dimensions: 19-1/2 x 24 in. - 50 x 61 cm.; Scale: 1" = 300'; Media: Pricking and India ink on paper with pencil notations and cloth backing; Sheets: 1 (Folder 29)
    Drawn By: P. P. Taliaferro, Asst. Eng.
  - Map - Map / Showing a Sub-Division of the Eastern Portion of the Fair Grounds of the Virginia State / Agricultural and Mechanical Society, at Richmond, Virginia, 10-C-2, 1897, Dimensions: 19 x 24 in. - 48 x 61 cm.; Scale: 1" = 100'; Media: Printed map on light paper; Sheets: 3 (Folder 29)
    Drawn By: James T. Redd & Son.
  - Map - Map Showing Hospital and Potter Sts. / From Fifth to Seventeenth, 12-A-5, 1902, Dimensions: 14-1/4 x 40-3/4 in. - 36 x 103 cm.; Scale: 1" = 50'; Media: India ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 27)
  - Map - Lots on Johnson's Island, Richmond, Va. / Property of the / Richmond Passenger & Power Co., 61-A-2a, 1903, Dimensions: 16-1/4 x 24 in. - 41 x 61 cm.; Scale: 1" = 40'; Media: Blueprint with red ink and pencil notations; Sheets: 1 (Folder 27)
  - Map - Map of the City of Richmond - Va. / Showing / Present Ward & Precinct Boundaries, 52-B-1, 1904, Dimensions: 18-1/2 x 29 in. - 47 x 74 cm.; Scale: 1" = 1000'; Media: India ink and blue ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 26)
    Drawn By: Compiled by H.P. Beck - Civil Engineer - Richmond, VA.
  - Map - [Map of area on north and south side of the James River at the Mayo Bridge], 14-C-3, 1905, Dimensions: 30-1/2 x 76 in. - 77 x 193 cm.; Scale: 1" = 50'; Media: India ink, red ink, an blue ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 29)
    Drawn By: Drawn by / W.B. Bates / Asst. City Engr.
  - Map - Map of the City of Richmond - Va. / Showing / Present Corporation Line as Established Dec. 6th. 1906 / also Existing Ward and Precinct Boundaries, 14-C-2, 1906, Dimensions: 25-1/4 x 37 in. - 64 x 94 cm.; Scale: 1" = 1000'; Media: India ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 29)
  - Map - Map Showing the Shield's Lot at the N.W. Cor. Of / 19th and Grace Streets., 48-A-2, 1906, Dimensions: 14 x 14-1/4 in. - 36 x 36 cm.; Scale: 1" = 30'; Media: India ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 27)
    Drawn By: City Engineer's Office / Richmond, Va. / H.P. Beck
  - Map - [Plan of block bounded by Broad, Marshall, 30th and 31st streets showing alleys and property owners], 44-A-1, 1907, Dimensions: 14 x 17-1/2 in. - 35 x 44 cm.; Scale: 1" = 30'; Media: India ink and red ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 27)
    Drawn By: Survey & map by F.T. Bates / Tracing by Fontaine Jones Mch. 2. 1907
  - Map - Map of Fairmont / Showing / Plan of Sewage System, 43-B-1, 1907, Dimensions: 30-1/4 x 29-1/2 in. - 77 x 75 cm.; Scale: 1" = 100'; Media: Pencil and India ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 26)
    Drawn By: By T.C Reed & Bro. / Jan 1st 1905 / Retraced in City Engineer's Office / Richmond, Va. / Mar 21 1907 / Fontaine Jones Del.
  - Map - Map / of / Hermitage Road / from / Broad St. to Railroad Ave. / Showing Adjacent Property Owners and Proposed Widening from 30 to 66 Feet, 47-A-1, 1907, Dimensions: 11 x 42-42-3/4 in. - 28 x 109 cm.; Scale: 1" = 40'; Media: India ink and red ink on linen; Sheets: 4 (Folder 27)
  - Map - Plan / Showing Proposed / Boundaries of / The Town of / Highland Park., 10145-B-1, 1908, Dimensions: 36-1/2 x 21-1/2 in. - 93 x 54 cm.; Scale: 1" = 300'; Media: India ink and blue ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 28)
    Drawn By: T. Crawford Redd & Bro. / Surveyors & Engineers
  - Map - City of Richmond Va. / Map of Hermitage Road / from / Broad Street to Railroad Ave., 20-D-1, 1908, Dimensions: 19-1/4 x 58-1/2 in. - 49 x 148 cm.; Scale: 1" = 30'; Media: India ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 27)
    Drawn By: City Engineer's Office / Richmond, Va. / Fontaine Jones / Asst. City Engr. / Del.
  - Map - Map of Property / Between / James River and Kanawha Canal / and / Cherry, Spring and Arch Sts., 22-D-1, 1908, Dimensions: 33 x 29-1/2 in. - 84 x 75 cm.; Scale: 1" = 100'; Media: India ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 29)
  - Map - Sewerage Map / of Manchester Va. Now / Washington Ward / Richmond Va., 62-B-1, 1910, Dimensions: 28-1/2 x 46 in. - 72 x 116 cm.; Scale: 1" = 200'; Media: 1 India ink on linen, 1 blueprint with red pencil notations (damaged); Sheets: 2 (Folder 102)
  - Map - Map / of Manchester Va now / Washington Ward / Richmond, Va, 62-B-1, 1910, Dimensions: 28-1/2 x 45-1/2 in. - 72 x 115 cm.; Scale: 1" = 200'; Media: India ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 27)
  - Map - Plan of Fourteenth Street / Between / Dock St. & North Abutment of Mayo's Bridge, 65-A-2a, 1910, Dimensions: 11 x 21 in. - 28 x 53 cm.; Scale: 1" = 50'; Media: 1 India ink and red ink on linen, 1 blueprint with pencil notations (heavily damaged; in two pieces); Sheets: 2 (Folder 26)
  - Map - City of Richmond Va. / Map of / North and South Sides of James River / at Mayo's Bridge / Showing Property to be Acquired for Approaches, 65-A-2e, 1911, Dimensions: 14 x 36-1/4 in. - 36 x 92 cm.; Scale: 1" = 50'; Media: Pencil, India ink, and yellow ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 27)
    Drawn By: Office of the City Eng'r. / Fontaine Jones Asst. Eng'r / Del.
  - Map - Map / of / Drewey Mansion Addition / near the / City of Richmond, 96-C-2, 1911, Dimensions: 16-1/2 x 35 in. - 42 x 89 cm.; Scale: 1" = 50'; Media: India ink on linen with pencil notations; Sheets: 1 (Folder 26)
    Drawn By: W.W. LaPrade, / Engineer & Surveyor
  - Map - Map /of / Bacon Quarter Branch / from / Lombardy to Sledd St., 48-B-3, 1911, Dimensions: 23-3/4 x 38 in. - 60 x 96 cm.; Scale: 1" = 50'; Media: India ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 27)
    Drawn By: City Engr's Office
  - Map - Map of Hull Street / at South End of Mayo's Bridge, 65-A-2b, 1913, Dimensions: 20 x 15-1/2 in. -51 x 39 cm.; Scale: 1" = 50'; Media: 1 India ink on linen, 1 blueprint; Sheets: 2 (Folder 27)
    Drawn By: M. Bowers
  - Map - Contour Map of Portion of Block Between 24th and 25th Franklin and Grace Sts. / Grading done to fill slip in Marshall Square adjacent to Williamsburg Avenue, 49-C-3, 1915, Dimensions: 26-1/2 x 42 in. - 67 x 107 cm.; Scale: 1" = 10'; Media: Pencil, India ink, and colored inks on paper with cloth backing; Sheets: 1 (Folder 29)
  - Map - Chart Showing the / Distribution of Population / City of Richmond, 6-C-1, 1915, Dimensions: 32-1/2 x 38 in. - 83 x 97 cm.; Scale: None; Media: Printed map on paper with pencil notations (damaged); Sheets: 1 (Folder 29)
    Drawn By: Compiled and Mapped by / Bolton, Clarke & Pratt, Inc, Civil Engineers / Richmond, Virginia
  - Map - Map / Showing the Proposed Opening / of / Twentieth Street / from / Corporation Line to Brauer Lane, 116-C-2, 1915, Dimensions: 41 x 29-1/2 in. - 104 x 73 cm.; Scale: 1" = 50'; Media: Pencil, India ink, and yellow ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 27)